Rock, paper, scissors!
Damn it! Isagi won?
Then let's choose our positions starting with the winner, Isagi-kun.
I want to be a forward.
The first selection will be a tournament between the 5 teams in the same building.
The two teams with the highest scores will advance,
while the rest will be eliminated from Blue Lock.
Eliminated players will never again
be able to play for the Japanese national team.
However,
from the 3 eliminated teams,
the players who scored the most goals will not be eliminated.
If there is more than one player with the most goals,
fair play points will be checked,
and the player with fewer penalty points will continue.
Your own goals, or your team's victory?
Your decisions as a forward will be tested here.
This is a battle about creating soccer from scratch.
The first match will be in two hours, between Team X and Team Z.
Alright guys.
We'll play with this formation in the first match.
Let's win with center forward Isagi-kun as our base.
Understood.
Can we win by basing on Isagi, who is ranked pretty low?
Shut up, Igaguri.
I don't want to stay in defense, you know.
As long as we win, right?
I'm not complaining.
"As long as we win", is that so?
Can you even play goalkeeper?
I just lost at rock-paper-scissors, that's all.
When he said 'a battle to create soccer from zero',
what did he mean?
It's about time.
The Blue Lock match that will change my life is about to begin.
BUILDING 5, CENTRAL AREA
Team X has arrived.
CHAPTER 3: SOCCER'S 'ZERO'
All fouls in the first selection will be decided by the VAR system.
The first match of Building 5, consisting of two 45-minute halves,
Team X vs Team Z, let the match begin.
Scared, Isagi?
Let's have as much fun as possible, otherwise we can't win.
Okay.
He's right, I don't need to be scared.
After all, I'm at the very bottom of the rankings, 274th.
I just need to play and
rise up!
Should we pass back and attack again?
Hey! What are you doing, Raichi?
There was a rule that the top scorer wins, right?
I don't give a damn about the team.
I'll do this my own way.
You know your stuff, Raichi.
If that's the rules here,
I'll play for myself without any hesitation.
Kunigami, looks like we'll get along well.
What are you doing?
Pass it to me too!
Wait, what happened to our positions?
Get out of my way!
On your way.
Damn.
Your physique isn't bad.
It's my lucky day.
Look ahead.
They can't get along either?
What's going on here?
These idiots are only thinking about themselves.
This is a battle to recreate soccer.
That 'creating from zero' that guy talked about
was this kind of dogfight?
This isn't soccer.
What should I do?
Should I join them too?
He slipped through!
If you don't get out of my way
I'll kill you.
TEAM X - BL RANK 250, BAROU SHOUEI
I'll stop him!
He's coming. Is he going left?
A chip shot?
Damn, he got past me!
Sorry, Kuon. It's coming to you!
-Leave it to us!
-No problem, two on one.
Two nutmegs in a row?
What the hell is this guy?
He's both huge and skilled!
I couldn't even react.
Get it through your heads, you talentless bastards.
The ball is not my 'friend' or anything.
It's just a round slave that makes me stand out!
I am the king of the field.
Can we win against someone like this?
-Awesome!
-Well done, King Barou!
Aren't you the goalkeeper, dammit?
Do your job properly!
I've never been a goalkeeper before, what can I do?
They only scored one goal, pull yourselves together.
He's right. If we keep our positions and play with passes...
If we do that, because you're the forward
all the goals will be credited to you.
The losers can go to defense.
As soon as the ball comes to you, pass to me!
Screw you, pass to me!
-No, to me.
-No, pass to me!
Team Z, please continue the match.
Calm down.
The match just started.
And what are they testing us on anyway?
But whatever happens, I have to win.
As long as the ball doesn't go to him...
Bachira! Let's advance by passing between us.
Hey Igaguri, don't leave your position!
Are you dumb, Isagi? The top scorer survives.
You can only dream of getting a pass.
-Better luck next time!
-Hey, wait!
Now I understand the Blue Lock first selection.
It's a battle where you score goals with only your own skills!
Damn!
Idiot, I stole the ball.
Did you really lose it? I'll kill you!
You fool, Igaguri!
Everybody get back! We're defending!
Hey, let's pass to Barou and support him.
Don't you see their team play?
If we win as a team rather than individual scores, there's no problem!
You're right. Barou!
Leave the right wing to me!
I'll take the left!
We'll leave the defense to you!
We're screwed. They're starting to sync up.
Barou. Everyone mark Barou!
You're saying that, Igaguri?
Damn. We have to stop him!
Does it make sense for all you losers to crowd around me?
This won't work.
If we leave Barou alone,
he'll tear through our defense. But if we only focus on him,
-Come to that open space!
-the other players will be free!
Catch it, Iemon!
Hell yeah! That's the second!
Thanks, King Barou!
We're screwed. At this rate we'll lose.
They managed to become a team!
We lost the ball because of you, Igaguri!
But we can't even get along yet. We can't win like this.
I can't stand this anymore!
Until just a moment ago, they were in disarray too.
Because of him.
Barou's goal united them!
This is the battle to create soccer from zero.
If that dogfight is 'zero',
then Barou's breathtaking play is 'one'.
One more!
Then, around this 'one', a strategy to win is formed,
and a team emerges.
Was that the meaning of 'creating soccer from zero'?
If that's the case, we're done for.
As the score gap widens, they're thinking more about themselves.
In this situation, there's no one who can turn 'zero' into 'one'.
Moreover, the opposing team's bonds are getting tighter.
It's impossible now.
We've already
lost this match.
Ah, all we're doing is running around.
It's impossible to score 5 goals in 3 minutes.
But maybe we can score one, you and me.
Bachira.
The opponents have let their guard down being 5-0 up. It might be a one-time chance.
You in?
I'm in.
I'll turn this team's 'zero' into 'one'!
I'll draw them to me.
Then I'll send a long pass to you, and you'll finish.
Run, Isagi.
Towards the goal.
Okay, Bachira.
I'll score that goal!
What? Isagi-kun?
Even if turning back is impossible,
if someone scores a goal,
we can become a team around that person.
It means we'll turn 'zero' into 'one'.
Surround him!
Together with Bachira, I'll score that goal.
I'm sure this is the key to winning the next match.
So that's it, Isagi.
I'll be the light of Team Z!
Right on target.
-Yes.
-Nice pass, Bachira.
One on one.
I'll shoot!
Hey, number 11.
Don't steal my light.
I said I'm the king.
Get past me if you can, loser.
Why is he here? Did he figure out our plan?
What should I do? Should I try to get past?
But against him...
In a situation like this, what would a forward do?
Isagi! I'm behind you!
Pass to me!
-I'll shoot!
-I'm here!
Should I pass? No.
This is my battle!
If I'm going to survive Blue Lock,
if I'm going to live as a forward...
Nice pass, Isagi.
It's impossible to shoot from that distance.
That's it!
I passed involuntarily.
What do you think you're doing, Isagi? Why did you pass to Kunigami?
Compared to him, I was more open!
No, I was planning to shoot.
But for some reason, my body on its own...
Are you an idiot, man? What's the point of passing when you could shoot?
Don't, Raichi!
We scored a goal anyway!
Ha! Are you stupid too?
After someone else scores,
and on top of that losing 5-1, what's there to be happy about?
You heard the rules, right?
At the end of the day, the top scorer will win!
But you wasted that chance and passed!
What the hell did you come here for!
I don't know.
Because I made that pass involuntarily.
Hey, number 11.
Someone who gets scared in front of the goal can't be a forward.
You're just talentless.
Time's up.
Blue Lock Building 5 first match, ended with Team X's 5-1 victory.
What am I doing?
Wasn't I going to turn 'zero' into 'one'?
Am I
a failure as a forward?
Making Isagi the center forward was a mistake from the start!
Next match, I'll be it!
No, I'll be it. If I'm center forward, we can win.
By the way, I'm not playing defense again.
Trash should shut up.
You're the trash Isagi didn't pass to.
You wanna fight, punk?
Someone who gets scared in front of the goal can't be a forward.
You're talentless.
Why did I pass?
Since I came here, I still haven't changed.
What am I missing to survive Blue Lock as a forward?
-Pass to me!
-No, to me!
-Pass to me too!
-Pass to me first.
Cut it out already!
Kuon.
Don't you realize the situation?
We've already lost once.
In the first selection, every team will play against each other,
and only 2 teams will advance.
Assuming each team wins two matches and loses two,
everyone would have 6 points.
That means the points we need to win
is above that, 7.
That will be the threshold determining who advances.
So if we lose twice,
our elimination is only a matter of time.
We've already reached the point of "if we lose again, we're done".
If we don't plan how to win,
we'll really be finished.
Do you at least have a good plan?
No, not yet.
What the hell? You're all talk.
-But this way-
-There's a way.
I couldn't have scored that goal without Bachira and Isagi.
That could be a hint to winning.
Don't mess with me, musclehead! You just want to be the top scorer!
But it was amazing.
It was definitely the goal of the day.
-You're naked!
-If we do this a lot, we can win.
Right, Isagi? Right?
Bachira.
Are you dumb?
We can't constantly pull off that perfect shot!
Also, stop exposing yourself!
But seriously,
where have you seen a whole team made up of forwards?
I don't think everything he said is correct.
Chigiri.
After all, even though Ego says it's to win the World Cup,
he brought up the names Cristiano Ronaldo, Messi, and Cantona, but
none of them won the World Cup.
But still,
the phrase 'a battle to create soccer from zero'
I think might be a hint.
Look, guys.
Even though I don't know how we'll win yet,
I think I've understood soccer's 'zero'.
Spit it out, you talentless guy.
In that match, at the beginning, because everyone was thinking only of their own goal,
it was just like a dogfight.
I think that situation reflected 'zero'.
Like you said, you couldn't really call it soccer.
You're right.
What broke that 'zero' was Barou's goal.
With the impact of that play,
the path to goal was illuminated and they started playing as a team.
Barou, with his own talent, turned that dogfight that equated to 'zero' into 'one'.
Based on that,
a team can evolve into '10' or even '100'.
So what we need is the power to bring forth that 'one'.
And that's possible with an irresistible ego and talent.
If forwards are those who turn 'zero' into 'one',
then are the other positions those who turn 'one' into 'ten' or 'a hundred'?
So is it that Ego set up a system
where the top scorer can survive for us to understand this?
I think so.
Because of that rule, we, experiencing an ego explosion,
cast aside our positions and tactics,
and were driven to think only about scoring.
As a result, without our egos colliding, it's impossible for us to become a team.
Soccer,
Team,
are created by an unstoppable forward.
I'm sure that's what Ego was talking about.
Yes, yes. You made a good point.
Hello there, diamonds in the rough.
The second match of your building has been completed.
Team V defeated Team Y 8-0.
What? 8-0?
Wow.
You're on the right track, but
you don't seem to have grasped the part about turning 'zero' into 'one'.
First, let's talk about Japan.
Japanese people assign themselves tasks
and take pleasure in completing those tasks.
For example, one of the few sports Japan can compete in globally,
Baseball.
It has an inning system that separates offense and defense,
and is a sport with no physical contact on the field.
This sport, where everyone's role is clear,
suits the Japanese personality perfectly.
That's why we are strong.
But in soccer, things are different.
You are on an open field where offensive and defensive roles
can change instantly.
Moreover, there is a lot of physical contact.
It's a sport you can't win just by fulfilling your assigned tasks.
That's why individual performances,
individual talent, is necessary.
These days, the positions that Japanese soccer can be proud of
are midfielders and full-backs.
They work like dogs for the team,
turning the forward's 'one' into 'a hundred'.
Without the sacrifice of these players,
Japanese soccer wouldn't have even come this far.
And moreover, there would be no revolution.
So, diamonds in the rough, review your mindset.
Scoring a goal in soccer means shattering the structure of the opposing team.
In other words, forwards are destroyers.
Scoring a goal is the pinnacle of revolution
that disrupts your opponent's order.
Diamonds in the rough,
don't let the roles restrict you!
To turn 'zero' into 'one',
arm yourselves, forwards!
Discover it.
Discover the weapon that will tear your opponents apart
and bring destruction!
Think hard about what you can do with that body and mind of yours!
It's you and your weapons that will bring about the revolution called a goal!
Victory follows after that.
Weapon.
What we need to win this first selection.
Blue Lock, Extra Time!
A DAY IN BLUE LOCK
WAKING UP
Morning, Bachira.
MEGURU BACHIRA, YOICHI ISAGI
Pass it, King Kazu.
WARM-UP AND TRAINING
RENSUKE KUNIGAMI
Master of the training room, Kunigami Kinnikun!
TEAM TRAINING
Ah! Muscle cramp!
Damn it, that's the fifth one today.
You're trying to slack off, right?
No, it's definitely broken!
It's like a muscle strain or a compound fracture!
GURIMU IGARASHI
Don't eat with your hands, dammit!
So dirty! Use the chopsticks!
Okay.
Let's clean those hands, okay?
Are you his mom?
Mom Kuon!
What are you doing, Chigiri?
Hair care.
HYOMA CHIGIRI
What are you doing, Imamura?
Skin care.
YUDAI IMAMURA
SLEEP TIME
Are we sure he's asleep?
Look at that face.
I knew it wasn't broken.
You lying bastard!